我有一个好问题 因为我们刚完成坏融合
I have a good question. Since we just finished the Bad Fusion.
还有一些 尽管应用可能与技术技术不同
And some, although the application may vary from technical techniques, also
实际的大小 大多数时候 在文学作品中
practical size. Most of the time, in literature,
一个新的搜索 没有人真正谈论什么
a new search in it, nobody really talks about something
它们可以消除电恐惧 例如 如果你有一种适应性不强的材料 那么你就可以在电场的作用下 很快地将它高度极化
that they friends out electric fear, e.g., if you have material that is not highly adapting, and then you can highly polarize that at some point in the effect of the electric field, very soon.
所以没有人真正谈论它与未来的关系
And so nobody really talks about that in relation to that future.
是说电力燃料的贡献微不足道吗
Is it that the contributions from the electric fuel is to insignificant?
这也可以归结为材料的特殊性质
Well, it also could be a lumped into the particular properties of the material.
举个例子 比如 像锂 煤 一氧化碳经历金属绝缘体转变
So, for instance, for instance, like lithium, coal, monoxide undergoes a metal insulator transition.
所以当你依赖L-I-X-C-O时 是2 对吧
So when you depending on L-I-X-C-O, two, right?
作为一个简单的例子 不要回到 你知道 你知道 这么古老的材料 但是 为了简单的例子 对吧
As a, just a simple example, not to go back to, you know, you know, such an old material, but, uh, for simple example purposes, right?
化合物的响应 你知道 说到电场 和响应 你知道 基本上 当我们谈论 是的 是的 我们实际上是在谈论 像 电常数 对吧
The response of the compound, you know, speaking of electric field, and response to, you know, basically, when we talk about, yeah, yes, we're really talking about, like, the electric constant, right?
呃 这个材料的反应
Uh, the response of this material.
如果材料的反应不同 成分也不同
And it the material response differently, with different composition as well.
对吧 生活时间越长对生活时间越短 对吧
Right? As you liviate more versus as you liviate less, right?
这些材料的导电性和绝缘性可以分别提高
The materials can become, uh, more electrically conductive verses more insulating, so respectively.
因此 响应集中在性质中 测量值 你得到的值 集中在特定成分下材料的性质中
So there that response is lumped in the the properties, the measurement, the values that you get out, is lumped into the property of that material at that particular composition.
所以你必须在组成上进行分解 诱导特定的研究 而不是在尽可能相似的条件下 就像 你知道 没有你无法控制的聚合复制因为缺陷 你知道 成本 你知道 呃 缺陷 呃 因为你没有一直分解 或者在相同的生长条件下 你知道 基本上是尽可能地攻击相同的 你知道
So you'd have to really decompolute induce particular studies right at the composition, as opposed to um and under as similar conditions as possible, as in, you know, there's no polyranic copying that you couldn't control because of defects, you know, cost, you know, uh, defects, uh, because you didn't delitheate all the way, or the same growth conditions, you know, basically attack the identical as possible, you know.
所以 我认为 嗯 这是一种附加的组合到这一个值中 也就是 得到的表观扩散系数
So, I think, um, that is, is sort of substuminent lump into this one value, that is, the apparen't diffusion coefficient that get out?
是的 好的 谢谢你的问题 在我们继续之前 这是一个很好的暂停时间
Yes. Well, thanks for the question, which is a good time to pause before we move on.
因为我对观众也有压力 那就是 这是一个要求的话题 通常我不会偏离太多 但正如我之前在课程中提到的 如果它 你知道 如果一个话题是有意义的 或者是之前没有在课程表上的阐述或介绍 嗯 那么 你知道 我很乐意帮忙
Um, cause I also have oppression for the audience, which is, this was a requested topic, and typically I don't deviate too much, but as I had suggested earlier in the course, that, um, if it, you know, if a topic makes sense, or elaboration or introduction that was not on the schedule before, um, then, you know, I'm, I'm happy to oblige.
这是我们及时要求的
And this was requested at, you know, well, in a timely manner.
我还想问一下其他同学 关于这个技巧 你们有什么特别的问题想要回答吗
So, um, I also would like to ask the rest of the class, you know, are there specific questions about this particular technique that you are hoping to be address?
尽管我不得不说提出请求的人似乎并没有出席
Although I do have to say the the person that made the request does not appear to be an in attendance.
所以 嗯 所以我想没有什么特别的问题了
So, um. So I suppose there aren't any specific question.
所以我们现在就开始计划好的讲座
So we'll proceed with the planned lecture right now.
好的 就松弛时间的分布而言 这是另一种试图理解材料 电池 电化学电池本身发生的过程的技术
Okay, so in terms of distribution of relaxation time, this is yet another technique to try to understand the processes that that are going on in the material, in the battery, in the electrochemical cell itself.
我们已经谈了很多 是的 这是基础的一部分
So we've talked a lot about, yes, and it was part of the fundamentals of the Foundations
模块 因为它被广泛使用 所以你可以在这里看到文章数量的目录 你知道 包括A-S当然是随着时间的推移而增长的
module, because it's widely used. And so you could see here the drectory of the number of articles, you know, that have included A-S has certainly grown over time.
当然 这也与他所在领域的人数有关
But of course, this tracks with also the number of people that are in his field.
这个主题 你知道的
Uh, the subject matter, you know,
电池材料 你知道 越来越受欢迎
battery materials being, you know, increasingly popular and
紧迫的话题 所以它是有趋势的
pressing topic. So it trends with that.
所以它并没有偏离 你知道的 平均趋势
So it's not any, uh, it does not deviate from, you know, the the average trend.
但这就是说 是的 在阴茎 电化学和阴茎工艺中 他作为一种技术的使用越来越多
But that's all to say that, yes, in penis, electrochemical and penis craft be has been increasing as a technique that's used.
虽然解释数据 正如我们所看到的 要复杂得多 你知道 得到一些值 并将其与试图理解材料的基本原理相关联 就获得更高的分辨率而言 以真正理解特征 呃 频率 从而了解某些过程的特征时间尺度 并将其应用于现实世界的应用
Although interpreting the data, as we've seen, is much more complex than just, you know, getting some values out and correlating that with with trying to understand the fundamentals of the materials, in terms of getting higher resolution to really understand the characteristic, uh frequencies, and thus characteristic time scales of certain processes, and apply that to, you know, real world applications.
DT 至少对于锂电池社区来说 比yes技术更新生一点 它已经从这个领域被采用 你会卖给社区
DT has, at least for the lithium battery community, has been a little bit more nascent than that of the yes technique, and really it's been adopted from the field, you'll sell community.
所以在D-R-T中有很多假设 再一次 谨慎之后 这项技术应该非常小心
And so there's a lot of assumptions that go into D-R-T, and once again, after caution, this technique should be done with a lot of care um.
但如果做得好 你真的可以得到信号 使你能够解释电化学电池中到底发生了什么
But when that is done well, you really can get out signals that will enable you to interpret what's really happening in a in an electrochemical cell.
所以这是一篇非常好的近期论文
So it's a very good recent paper.
在过去的几个月里 它试图将这项技术应用于快速充电和检测用石墨的NMZ电池 以及检测 你知道 当镀锂发生时 这是快速充电的常见故障机制
Within the last few months, it came out on trying to fly the technique to fast charging and detection of um but NMZ full cells with graphite, and detecting, you know, when lithiumplating occurs, which is a common failure mechanism for fast charging.
所以我们要追踪的典型阻抗是sci 这些单独的过程是什么
And so the typical impedances that we would try to track to see is sci You know, what are these individual processes?
科学在发展吗 它在增长吗
Is sci developing? Is it growing?
它会随着时间而改变吗 你知道答案是肯定的
Is it changing over time? You know the answer is yes.
但它是如何随时间变化的呢
But how is it changing over time?
阻抗是如何随时间变化的
How is the impedence changing over time?
这对汽车的快速充电能力意味着什么
And what does that mean for a sells ability to fast charge?
你能检测到一个更大的堆栈模块级别 而不仅仅是一个细胞吗
And can you detect at A-A larger stack module level, beyond just one cell?
你知道 所以基本上一直在应用这种技术 试图了解你的模块什么时候会失效 或者 你知道 这个细胞的健康状态是什么
You know, so basically going all the way to the applying this technique to try to understand when is your module going to fail, or, you know, what is the state of health of of this cell?
所以这对终端用户来说是非常重要的问题
So that's really important questions for end users.
但更根本的是 D-R-T可以让你有更高的分辨率 也可以解释学生
But more fundamentally, D-R-T allows you to have higher resolution and also be able to interpret the students.
在速度上 在阴茎数据上 更好
Uh, in speed, it in penis data, uh, better.
好吧 所以晚上是你经常看到的地方
Okay, so the night was spots that you were used to seeing.
当有多个过程同时发生时 就意味着有多个时间常数
When there are multiple processes are happening, that means there are multiple time constants.
你可以看到半圆形的凹陷
And so you see this depression in the semicircle.
远离理想状态 就是 你懂的 一个漂亮的沙滩圈
Away from the ideality, which is just, you know, A-A, nice, sandy circle.
所以你能得到的 你知道 最重要的是 你在DRT中真正寻找的 是这个G-F-TAO函数 这个Fruithold函数 它精确地描绘了频率是什么
So what you can get out, you know, the punch line, is what you're really looking for in DRT, is this G-F TAO function, this Fruithold function that plots out exactly what the frequency is.
很明显这是隐藏在这里的
So that's obviously hidden in here.
这是高频 它是低频的
This is high frequency. It is low frequency.
你可以跟踪每一个数据点 并使用等效电路来解析 试图理解我们之前讨论过的时间内容
And you can track each data point and resolve using equivalent circuits to try to understand the the time contents that we've talked about before.
你知道 它在扩散范围内吗
You know, is it in the range of diffusion?
是沃伯格和学生吗
Is it a warberg and pudent?
你知道 是通过S-E-I抵抗吗
You know, is it uh, resistance through the S-E-I?
所以我们可以解释和拟合奈奎斯特图和荷伊图等等
So we can interpret and fit Nyquist plots and loady plots and so on so forth.
但另一种表示是D或T 你马上就能看到松弛时间的分布
But the other representation is this D or T, where you see immediately the distribution of the relaxation times here.
这是锁刻度力
So this is on the lock scale force.
然后你可以试着把这些峰值和一些噪音结合起来 然后把它们和物理过程联系起来 比如锂的形成 R-S-E-A的形成
So then you could try to fit these uh peaks that you see here with some noise um, and then nap them to physical processes like lithium play, R-S-E-A formation.
就方法而言 与 呃 是的 是的 你知道 对于一个 呃 R-C过程 很有竞争力
So in terms of the methodology, in comparison to, uh, yeah, yes, you know, for a two uh, R-C process, so competitive.
还不是恒相元素
Not a constant phase element yet.
就是一些典型的过程 比如两个R-C过程
So just something typical, like two R-C processes.
你看到一些东西 你知道 一个典型的夜间测验情节是这样的
You see something, you know, a typical night quiz plot that would look like this.
我们之前讨论过 平行的 R-R-C 愉快的R-C看起来是这样的 你在等效电路中有一些整体的元素 你有特定过程中特定元素的时间内容
And we've, uh, we've talked previously about, you know, in parallel, you know, R-R-C, pleasant R-C would look something like this, where you some overall the elements in your equivalent circuit, and you have the time content of that particular element of the particular process.
嗯 行动
Uh, act
正确的 你可以这样做
right. So, so you could do that.
你可以画出尸体的分布图 你会得到
You can plot the bodi plot, you get the
这里也是典型的频率 好吗
typical frequency here as well. OK?
但是在使用derT方面的改进是提高了分辨率
But the improvement in terms of using der T is the increased resolution.
这里你可以看到 基本上是一个疑点 一个函数
So here you could see, basically A-A doubt, a function.
你会得到直接函数 这是解析形式
You will direct function, where that's for analytical form.
你得到这两个 呃 这两个数据点非常清晰 很好地解决了问题
You get these two, uh, these two data points where it's very clear and well resolved.
这是两个 所以频率没有扩散
These are the two. So there isn't a spread in the frequency.
这很清楚 这就是解析形式 但它是数值解
It's very clear. So that is the the analytical form, but it solved numerically.
如果你看 你知道 你试着与很多RC元素相匹配 假设你超越了 假设你有两个以上的过程 你试着用你认为在一个特定细胞中发生的尽可能多的过程来模拟数据
If you look at, you know, the is and you try to butt and fit basically with a lot of RC elements, let's say you go beyond to, let's say you have more than two processes, and you try to model the data with as many processes as you think are happening in a particular cell.
你知道 没必要只局限于两三个人 对吧
You know, there's no need to just limit ourselves to the two or three, right?
假设在假设的世界中有一个终点 当你把它映射到 嗯 阻力作为时间常数的函数时 你会得到一个类似于避免类型的函数 或者你可以用相同数量的DRT来拟合避免函数的数据点
Let's say there's end in the hypothetical world, When you map it onto, um, the resistance as a function of the time constant, you get something that looks like avoid type of function, or data points that you can fit to avoid function with DRT with the same number of elements.
你能做的就是把解析形式转化为数值形式
Um, what you can do is going from the analytical to the numerical form.
你也可以画出相同类型的数据 但你可以试着在这里拟合电路 得到更高的分辨率
You could also plot that the same type of data, but then you could try to fit the circuit here and get higher resolution out.
这就是最基本的运算
Okay, so that's, you know, the the fundamental the operations.
这是操作的基本理论
That's the fundamental theory in terms of the operation.
真正正确的是 你知道 用is测量你的系统然后你得到的是这些光谱
What really happens right is, you know, measure your your system with the IS and then what you get out are these spectra.
我们已经看到了这张夜景图
And so we've seen the nightwise plot there.
你可以在D或T中加入某种类型的模型你如何 如何求解这个解析函数
You can fit in a certain type of model into the D or T And how do you, how do you solve this analytical function?
对吧 如何解这个函数来得到你的GEO图呢
Right? How do you solve this function to get out your, um, your GEO tow?
有很多种数学方法 但这就是我要说的
Well, there are a variety of mathematical ways, but that's all to say.
你知道 你可以用变换或者矩阵组织来试着得到这些值 最流行的是这个 去掉正则化过程
You know, you apply either for you transform or a matrix organization to try to get the values out, the most popular being this, um, taken off regularization procedure.
但这就是我要说的 它们都是统计概率类型的技术
But that's all to say. They're all statistical probability type techniques.
好吧 这就是他们要做的 这就是他们要做的
Okay? That's all they, that's all they are to try to fit.
如果我有一个电路 一个有许多元件的等效电路 它如何与阻抗谱相匹配 然后在一天结束时生成a-d-r-t-a图
If I have one circuit that, you know, one equivalent circuit with a number of components, you know, how does that fit the the impedance spectra, and then produce A-D-R-T-A plot at the end of the day.
那么这个特殊的失败是什么呢 我想说不是失败
So what the downfall of this particular Well, I would say not the downfall.
我收回了那句话 我会考虑到这个签名的局限性 仔细地问我 这个技术是什么
I took that back. I would take the limitation of this signature and ask me, done with care, is that this technique is?
当你有低端和高端的过程时 就像在材料中扩散一样 是很有挑战性的
Is challenging when you have processes that are the low end and the high end, so like diffusion through the material.
所以你的战争工作阻抗需要一些处理 这样你得到的阻碍结构 你必须基本上切断这些数据 然后把它们全部取出来
So your war work impedence is going to um need some processing so that the impeding structure that you get out, you really have to basically cut off that data and just take it out altogether.
对吧 这是假设自行车不是贡献者的一部分
Right? That's part of the assumption that bike isn't contributor.
然后你可以模拟这种鲁莽行为然后把数据输入到像matLab这样的软件中 你知道 像D-R-T这样的代码工具是非常可用的 所以它会分析数据并得出这个
And then you can actually simulate that impudence and then input that data into software like mat Lab, you know, code like D-R-T tools are very available so that will analyze the data and spit out this.
对不起 我是本地人 因此 在模拟数据方面 在他们看到的其他东西中 有一个非常有用的应用笔记来自生物供应商的共同潜力
GT Sorry, g of town. So in terms of simulating data, there's very helpful application note from the biological A common potential at vendor amongst other things that they saw.
但是如果你有 你知道 一个像这样的R-Q电路 这里有一个恒相元件
But if you were to have, you know, an R-Q circuit like this, where you have here a constant phase element
而不仅仅是容量 如果你有三种不同的情况 其中一个 你有一个
instead of just a capacity, if you were to have three different scenarios, where one, you have one
时间常数 也许第二个回路有两个时间常数 也许第三个回路也有
time constant, maybe two time constants for this 2nd circuit, and maybe a 3rd circuit here, uh, that also,
从肉眼看 它有两个时间常数 对吧
you know, just by eye, looks like it has two time constants, right?
所以有些东西是可以衡量的
So there's some things that you can gauge.
你可以解决这些时间意识是什么
You can resolve what these time conscious are.
看看松弛时间 对吧
And look at the relaxation times, right?
看看分布
Look at the distribution.
所以如果你看一下模拟的G-F-TAO 你会发现这是理论和数据
So if you look at the simulated G-F TAO, you see that's the theoretical and the data.
理论上的是蓝色的
So the theoretical is the blue.
拟合数据 抱歉不是拟合数据 而是UM DRT工具的数据 看起来是这样的 UM 它是这样的 在红色的图中有一点噪声
The fitted data as the, sorry not to fitted data, but the UM, the data from DRT tools, would look something like, UM, it like this, where there's a little bit of noise in the red plot here.
所以如果你期望 你知道 一个时间常数 你得到它 你可以准确地跟踪特征频率是什么
So if you expect, you know, one time constant, you get that, and you can track exactly what the characteristic frequency is.
你是否期望 你知道 你可以在这里看到 至少理论的比实际的TAO的g更容易解决
Do you expect to, you know, you could see here that at least theoretical is much more well resolved than the real g of TAO.
如果你有另一个电路 他们应该说电路3
And then if you have another circuit, they should say Circuit three.
你有第三个电路 那里也有时间常数的分布
You have a 3rd circuit where there is also a distribution of time constants.
但是 你知道 它更分散
But, you know, it's more spread out.
假设这是一个电路3 然后你可以 嗯 解出这个 所以我想讨论这个特殊的例子 因为它是
Let's say this a circuit three here, then you can, uh, resolve that UM And so I wanted to talk about this particular example because it's um one.
这是最近的研究
It's extremely recent for this type of study.
真正有趣的是你可以对快速损伤做这种分析
And what's really interesting is that you can do these type of analysis for fast hurting.
E-S通常是介于 取决于你的频率范围 对吧
So E-S typically takes between, depending on your frequency range, right?
所以你要把频率降低 比如十万赫兹 降到 十兆赫
So you're going down, uh, you know, like a hundred kilohertz, to, what, ten millards?
我可以花 五 六 十分钟
I could take, you know, five, six, uh, 10 min.
如果是1毫米 我可以花20分钟
If you're going on the one milliers, I could take 20 min.
对吧 所以 如果你在快速充电 你想做 呃 阻抗萎缩分析 看看失效机制 或者可能导致电化学电池失效的机制 然后你想要能够相对快速地执行这些测量
Right? So, if you're fast charging, and you want to do, uh, impedence tratrophically analysis, to look at failure mechanisms, or mechanisms that could trend towards failure than of the electrochemical cell, then you want to be able to perform these measurements relatively quickly.
所以这是一个展示 这个研究的新颖之处在于 你知道 你可以相对快速地做实验 避免典型的 你知道 15分钟的松弛时间来检测石墨上的锂镀层
So this is a demonstration where what's novel about the study is that, you know, you can do the experiment relatively fast and avoid typical, you know, 15 minute relaxation periods for detecting lithium plating on graphite um.
这项研究的另一个好处是 T年不仅仅是一个分析 或者它与另一种技术相关 这种技术将真正精确地指出发生的化学反应 试图理解 你知道 三种可能发生的物理过程更好地列在这里
And what's also really, uh good about this study is that the year T is not just an analysis, or it's class correlated with another technique that will really pinpoint the chemistry of what's happening, to try to understand, you know, the three physical processes that could potentially be happening better listed here.
还有它的敏感性 你知道 你能多快发现锂电镀的开始
And the sensitivity too. You know, how quickly can you detect the onset of of lithium plating?
你知道 如果你有一定比例的容量 你可以检测到我们 你知道 如果我在早期检测到这个信号 我就确切地知道在快速充电中会发生什么
You know, if you have a certain percentage of the capacity where you detect us, you know, if I detect this signal early on, I know exactly what's going to happen in, you know, at fast charging.
这对于电动汽车的电池组分析来说是非常强大的 对吧
So that's really powerful, you know, for electric vehicle battery pack analysis, right?
所以 嗯 但它也指出了真正基本的理解在石墨颗粒的界面发生了什么 基本上是进入的锂离子 你知道
So, um. But it also points to really fundamental understanding what's happening at the interface of the graphite particle, and basically lithy myons that are coming in, you know.
所以典型的过程是 你知道 如果锂金属沉积 导致 比如说 长丝生长 观察长丝生长
And so the typical processes that one thinks about is, you know, if lithium metal is depositing, right, leading to, let's say, filament growth, looking at filament growth.
因此 你知道 基本上是最终做空这一切 对吧
And thus, you know, essentially shorting this all eventually, right?
互动如何 锂金属与固体智能界面的反应性如何
How interactive? How reactive is the Lithian metal with with a solid intellectual interface?
这种坚实的知识分子界面会成长吗
And does this solid intellectualite interface grow?
嗯 它有多动态
Um? And how dynamic is it?
所以这个S-E-I形式的传递层 可以提升我自己的结构 呃 使我的阿姨们受益 通过迁移来抑制任何 呃 任何更有害的副反应
So this S-E-I forms of a passating layer that enables, looking at lifting my own formation, UH, to elipie my aunts, to to migrate through and suppress any, uh, any more deleterious side reactions.
所以我们想知道 你知道 sci发生了什么 我们也想知道sci是否分层 或者部分分层 这会增加阻抗 因为现在你失去了接触电阻
So we want to know, you know, what's happening with sci You know, we also want to know if the sci is delaminating um, or even partially delaminating, which it will increase impedence, because now you are losing contact resistance.
然后我们还想知道 锂金属沉积是什么
And then we also want to know, you know, is the Lithian metal deposition?
当锂离子进入 这些锂 金属锂形成 这些形成 黑色阻挡 阻挡 额外的途径
UH As Lithiumians come in and these lithium, the lithium metal forms, does these UH Does the formation, black block, block, additional pathways to
这个黑色图形粒子
this black graphic particle um here,
对吧 所以 如果是这样 那就是
right? And so, if so, that's
这是一个很重要的结论 因为很明显 这影响了
an important um, a conclusion to reach, because that affects, obviously, the act of
材料 石墨ano 和
material, the graphite ano, and
其循环能力为后续
its ability to cycle for subsequent
电荷放电 所以有很多讨论 你知道 D或T作为电荷状态的函数而不是健康状态的函数
charge discharge. So there's a lot of discussion about, you know, D or T as a function of the state of charge instead of health.
所以 这是我们在补充文件中提供的定义之一 我在第一节课上讨论过的文件 但我要在这里强调一下 只是为了确保我们都在同一页上并且对这个定义有最近的记忆 对吧
And so, uh, this is one of the definitions that we provided in a supplementary um, a document that I discussed for our very 1st course lecture, but I'm going to highlight it here, just so I make sure we're all on the same page and have recent memory of this definition, right?
所以电荷的状态 当我们讨论如何给电池充电时 我们实际上是在讨论电池中剩余的容量 它与总容量的比值
So the state of charge. When we talk about, what is to say to charge um of a battery, we're really talking about the capacity that remains in the battery as it's ratio to the total capacity.
用百分比表示 所以乘以一个百分比 这个 这个分数
And it's reported in percent. So multiplied by a percent, this, this fraction.
所以如果我们看 一个典型的Govanic面 这里是一个循环图 我们看到这里 这将是这个对应于100%的soc
So if we look at, you know, a typical Govanic side, a cycling plot here, we see here, this would be this correspond to soc of 100 %.
在这里 如果我们看一下总容量 假设它在这个数字4 这大约是50%
Here. If we look at the total capacity, let's say it's at this number four here, this is about 50 %.
这大约是10% 因为剩下的不多了 即使电压高得多 对这个例子来说
This is about 10 %, because there isn't a whole lot left, even though the voltage is much higher, right for this particular um example.
这是在放电之后 然后是充电
So that's upon discharge and then charge.
这是相对于容量的
So and that's relative to capacity.
这与能量的电荷状态无关
That's not relative to the state of charge for energy.
如果我们讨论能量 我们会取曲线下的面积 看起来会有点不同 对吧
If we were talking about energy, we would take the area under the curve, which would look a little bit different, right?
这50%不会在这里
This 50% wouldn't actually be here.
可能更像是在这里 你知道 所以 嗯 这就是区别所在
Probably would be more like here, say, you know, so that, um, so that's, that is the point of distinction.
但是我在这里讨论的电荷状态 它与容量有关 所以是社会容量
But the state of charged I was talking about here, it relatives to the capacity, so s soc capacity.
这只是一个示意图 但是我发现我觉得很有用 所以我把它包括在这里 你知道 电池的充电状态 从100%放电一直到零 然后再回到100%
And so here's just a schematic, but I found that I thought was quite useful, so I included it, UM here to see, you know, the state of charge for battery, from discharge a hundred percent all the way down to zero and then back again to a hundred percent.
在健康状态方面 这里我们要讨论的是电池的最大可用电量与额定容量的比值 也用百分比表示
And in in terms of state of health, here we want to talk about the maximum charge that's available in a battery as a ratio of the rated capacity, and reported as also percent.
这里我只是复制了你们在前一张幻灯片中看到的pay-save电压代码
So here I've just copying pay save the voltage code that you saw in the previous slide.
这条黑色曲线是100%的
So this is at, you know, the black curve is at a hundred percent.
呃 健康状况 我们说 嗯 接下来的周期 健康状况现在是90%
Uh, state of health, let's say, um subsequent cycles, the state of health is now at 90 %.
所以这里的容量是原来的9%
So the capacity here is 9% of what it once was.
所以在电荷态方面 然而 在我们讨论过的这些不同的点 它们说的是一样的
So in terms of the state of charge, however, at these various points that we've talked about, they say the same.
只是现在的健康状况是90%的国家收费仍然是100 5010
Is just the state of health is now 90% of the state charge is still a hundred, 5010.
零 好吧 然后 你知道 如果能力日期发生得比你看到的更剧烈 这可能是健康状态是50%
Zero. Okay? And then more subsequently, you know, if the capacity date is is occurring even more drastically that you see here, this could be state of health is is 50 %.
这就是我们讨论的区别
So that's the distinction that we talk about.
当你谈到负责的状态时 我说的是健康
When you talk about state of charge, I say to health.
好 回到我们电镀锂的例子
Okay, so back to our lithium plating example.
从阻抗数据 我们可以看到 我们可以绘制gf道 我们可以看到 作为日志频率的函数 我们可以看到 有一个过程 你知道 在10的-oneish 然后在更高的频率 倾向于做02 10四笔 所以用的时间匹配过程 我们希望在这些时间尺度 我们可以期待生活扩散 呃 这个时候 大众交通工具
Here from the impedance data, we can see that we can plot the G-F TAO, and we can see, as a function of the log frequency, we can see that there is a process, you know, at ten to the minus oneish, and then at higher frequencies, tend to do 02:10 to the four pen And so in terms of matching the time scale with processes that we expect during these time scales, we can expect a living diffusion, UH, at this time scale, mass transport.
我们可以期待电荷转移 锂离子的转移电阻插入并镀到石墨材料上
Well, we can expect charge transfer, UH transfer resistance of lithiumine inserting and plating onto the graphite material.
这就是氧化还原锂
So that's the lithium redox um.
然后我们也可以期待我的迁移发生在10的4次方的智力界面上
And then we can also expect with the my migration that occurs through the intellectually interface at ten to the 4th.
这是非常快的 好的 现在这里的循环速率是c2o5 所以对于这个特定的例子来说 这是相对较慢的 对吧
Okay, so that's extremely fast. Okay, now the cycling rate here is C-O five, so that's relatively slow for this particular say, right?
当我们谈论路径时 我们谈论的是至少一个座位 你知道 这个研究从 看 一直到16
When we talk about path, we're talking about at least one seat, you know, this study goes from to, see, all the way up to um 16.
好的 但是第一个字母的首字母 你知道 慢速率
Okay, but the 1st initial, just looking at, you know, a slow rate.
我们
We
已经看到了一些趋势在20到100之间的充电状态 对吧
already see some trends um in terms of at state of charge between 20 and a hundred right?
确实有很小的变化 相对于 你知道 在质量传输频率上 相对于这里发生的
There is really minor changes relative, you know, at the mass transport frequency, relative to what's happening here at the
费用转移和sci
charge transfer and sci for
20%到100%的soc只有当我们过度创造的时候 在这里 我们看到一些重大的变化 这可能发生在这些快速充电电池上
20 to a hundred percent soc it's only when we overly create and here in a hundred and 20% that we see some major changes, and that can happen for these fast charging cells.
所以在潜在的静态阻抗方面 当你可以 当你跟踪 sci的电阻和电荷转移的电阻值时 实际上sci的电阻并没有很大的变化
So in terms of potential static impedence, when you can um, when you track the um, the resistance of the sci versus the resistant values of the charge transfer, there really isn't a whole lot changed in terms of resistance from the sci.
但是当soc超过100时 这里有一个相当大的下降 所以当你过度缓解时
But there is quite a drop right here when soc is beyond a hundred, so when you're over alleviating.
所以垃圾传递实际上在减少 不好意思 阻力在减少 当你放松的时候
Okay, so so the trash transfer is actually decreasing, sorry, the resistance is decreasing, um here when you're reliviate.
好吧 那么这到底是什么呢 在你开始快速充电的时候要做什么呢
Okay, well, what what is that really, um, uh, have to do in terms of when you start to then fast charge?
嗯 如果动力学对于um电荷转移来说真的很快 那就意味着你真正看到的不是sci的形成 而是锂的剥离和电镀
Well, if the kinetics is really fast for the um charge transfer, that means what's what you're really looking at is not the sci formation, but it's the lithium stripping and plating.
所以这将是我们继续讨论的主要因素
So that's going to be the dominant factor um for, uh, when we move on.
当我们转向快速充电时 需要注意的是 你知道 就快速充电而言 速度实际上会对锂电镀产生重大影响
Things to look out for for when we moved to fast charging, and, you know, in terms of fast charging, where which rate will actually really significantly impact the lithium plating.
所以这里你可以看到石墨电阻 如果你在2摄氏度 SCI的电阻和S-E-I的初始电阻归一化 所以这是SCI不是作为电荷状态函数的变化是非常小的 你知道 2摄氏度相对于4摄氏度在60
So here you can see the graphite resistance if you're at two C, the resistance of SCI and as normalized to the initial resistance of S-E-I, so that's SCI not that change as a function of state of charge is pretty minor at, you know, two C relative to that of four C in 60.
所以你真的需要研究至少4摄氏度的速率 抱歉 4摄氏度和60摄氏度的速率 但是 你知道 5%的电荷
So you really want to be studying these rates at at least four C, that's when, sorry, four C and 60 already at But, you know, 5 %, say charge.
你会发现这种情况在急剧上升 对吧
You see this picking up pretty dramatically, right?
这就是你如何设计实验来缩小范围的方法
So that's how you can design your experiment to narrow in the scope.
他们就是这么做的
So that's exactly what they did.
这是一个完整的细胞和它们的种子
You know, they did Here you see a full cell and em seed.
我把两个作为阴极 石墨作为阳极 然后是铝锂电极的参考 在4摄氏度 真正有趣的是 在20 20%的soc之后 sci的电阻真的增加了
I threw two for the cathode, graphite for the anode um, and then a reference of aluminum lithium electrode at four c And what's really interesting is that after 20, 20% soc the resistance really, of the sci really increases.
嗯 在这里 这是递增的
Uh, here. Okay, so that's increasing.
这告诉你 如果你的s
So that that telling you, if your s.
我 你知道 那是建立的 抵抗正在建立
e. I., you know, that is built, the resistance is building up.
这意味着有一个浓度贪婪 它在增加 它在增加 但这不是唯一的特征
That means there's a concentration greedy that that's increasing, and that's building up, um And but that's not the only feature.
你知道 如果你看到电荷转移电阻和S-E-I的原因 这并不是锂存在的唯一迹象
You know for if you're seeing charge transfer resistance and also reasons of S-E-I, that's not the only indication that there's lithium.
有 呃 一些事情也可能 呃 正在发生
There's, uh, a number of things that can also, um, be be happening.
好的 从他们的D-R-T和阻抗分析来看 相信我 他们可以开始排除某些特定的过程 比如 你知道 如果S-E-I的风险在增加 你知道 这是否意味着SCI也在增长
Okay, so from their D-R-T and impedance analysis across reference was to trust me, you know, they can start to then rule out certain a certain processes, such as, you know, if the risk of S-E-I is increasing, you know, does that mean the SCI is also growing?
嗯 看起来不是这样的 因为它是SCI或生长 通常有一些液体电解质的分解 然后形成 这有助于SCI的生长 你可以从质量中检测到二氧化碳 但是检测到的量是 你知道 相当相当恒定的
Well, it appears that that's not the case, because it's SCI or growing that usually having some decomposition of the liquid electrolyte, and then that's forming, that's helping to grow this sci is you can detect carbon dioxide from mass back, but the amount that's detected is, you know, pretty pretty constant.
所以这并不指向第一种机制
So that really doesn't point towards this 1st mechanism.
应变是a 是一种可能性 对吧
Um strain is a, is a possibility, right?
因为他们确实增加了休息时间
Because they do add ocb resting period.
所以 你知道 他们已经做了这种类型的充电 放电 你知道 三到六次循环
And so, you know, they've done this type of um charging, discharging for a, you know, three up to six cycles.
所以 你知道 要真正知道这种观察是否指向事实 还需要做更多的衰老研究
So, you know, more aging studies would have to be done to really know if this type of observation is pointing to the fact
你的脊髓实际上是分层 但它开始指向那个方向
that your sci is actually delaminating, but it's starting to point towards that.
然后另一个 你想看到的另一个过程是 你知道 这个机制是否在道德上阻止了介子的扩散
And then the other, the other process that you want to see is, you know, is is this mechanism blocking, morally, the myons from diffusing um?
这是有可能的 但是
And it's possible, but you know, the
当你看到他们的分析结果时 你会发现
in terms of, when you look at the poor volume, their analysis
指出了这样一个事实 锂离子的数量 我实际上会阻止的离子 它们会占据空间 你知道 在这个材料的小体积中 是非常微不足道的
points to the fact that the amount of lithiums, that ions I would actually block, that would occupy the space the poor volume, you know, in in this material, is pretty insignificant.
所以impedience数据是指向一个事实 那就是 你知道 潜在的分层 但是 但是它的部分 和压力 随着时间的推移 实际上可以轻松的如果你有一个休息时间 现在 之后将它应用于实际电池并试图读出数据并分析 你知道 如果你可以收集阻抗嗯 看看 你知道 如果你 如果你是阴极电接口的阻力减少 并且在ano位点上的太阳能电界面在增加
So the impedience data is really pointing towards the fact that there's, you know, potential delamination, but, but it's partial, and and the strain, over time, actually can be relaxed if you have a just a resting period, right after now, applying it to actual battery packs and trying to read out the data and try to analyze, you know, if you can just collect impedence um and look at, you know, if you're, if you're resistance of the cathod electrical interfaces is decreasing, and the solar electrical interface on the ano site is increasing.
这真的是在告诉你 有锂电镀 还有什么时候
Is that really telling you that there's, uh, that there's lithium plating, and when?
在你骑车的过程中 你的充电状态是什么
At which point, basically during your cycling, there's your state of charge?
你知道 你多早知道
You know, how early can you tell?
你知道 它看起来就像这里
You know, and it looks like here.
你可以看到平稳期从25%开始 有些在20%到30%之间 比如说收费
You can see the plateau um starting at about 25 %, you know, some from where between 20 and 30 %, say charges.
那还挺早的 你可以在森林的早期就知道是否有观察和电镀
That's pretty early. You can tell if there's looking and plating pretty early at foresy.
所以知道一种技术是非常强大的
So that's pretty powerful to to know of a technique.
所以这是这个研究的一个片段强调了阻抗对cascopy的价值 还有drat快速充电 这与
So so that's one snippet of this study highlighting the the value of of impedence for cascopy, and also drt AT fast charging, which is pretty relevant for.